VU MINH TRUONG

JUNIOR JAVA DEVELOPER

+84-967-057-664 | vuminhtruongvmu18@gmail.com | https://vuminhtruong.github.io/portfolio/

SUMMARY

As a Java Developer with over 2 years of experience, I have been passionate about programming since my school years and always maintain a strong sense of responsibility in my work. I enjoy solving logical problems, and continuously learning new technologies. I strive to apply my knowledge, experience, and self-learning ability to contribute to projects, especially in developing optimized, and secure backend systems

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Java Spring Boot	Angular	RabbitMQ	Kotlin
SQL Sever	Firebase	Redis	Flutter

TypeScript Design Patterns Docker

EXPERIENCE

Soft Dream

Mar 2024 - Present

Job Description:

- Develop and optimize stalled computational processes involving large data volumes to enhance system performance and minimize processing time.
- Assist in resolving complex issues, such as financial report discrepancies, to ensure data accuracy in accounting operations.
- Develop administrative and support modules to help users address data errors efficiently.
- Implement a flexible role and data-switching feature between subsidiary companies to support complex permission scenarios.
- Develop import and export functionalities for accounting data operations.
- Design Excel report templates, PDF templates using JasperReports, and HTML templates
- Implement asynchronous functionalities and optimize the reporting system

Development Skills:

- Enhancing skills in Spring Boot, Angular, SQLSever, Redis, RabbitMQ, WebSocket
- Message Queue & Asynchronous Processing
- Solving Race Condition Problems, Batch Processing Skills, Lock, DeadLock, SQL Programming Skills, Query Optimization
- · Design Pattern: Observer, Mediator, Chain of responsibility, OutBox, Saga
- · Monitoring & Logging Skills
- Teamwork skills, collaborating with a team of five members on highly complex modules

Dratini Technology

Jan 2023 - Jan 2024

Job Description:

- Analyzed system functions, debugged, and resolved backend issues to ensure smooth operation
- · Design a dashboard page and implement a highly reliable user management solution
- Develop a catalog system for agents in inventory management
- Develop effective teamwork skills, closely collaborating with a team of 6 members on complex projects

Development Skills:

- · Proficient in Spring Boot, Angular, MySQL, Redis, Docker
- Design Pattern, Hibernate, JWT, CronJob
- Teamwork, troubleshooting skills
- Enhance analytical and problem-solving skills by participating in all stages from design to implementation and debugging
- Learn to design and implement a user management system using a microservices architecture

Job Description:

- Developing APIs
- Worked in a Scrum model, participated in Sprint Planning and Daily Stand-ups
- Defining functional requirements for modules
- Research the structure and business logic of sales management

Development Skills:

- Java Core, RESTful API, JSON, HTTP methods
- SQL queries, JPA, Hibernate
- Understand the Scrum model
- Requirement Analysis & Research Skills
- · Skills for working in a professional environment

EDUCATION

National Research University ITMO

Oct 2018 - June 2023

- · Major in Software Engineering
- Thesis on "Building an Asynchronous Blog Application (Spring Boot and RabbitMQ)"
- GPA: 4/5

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Languages: English, Russian
- Awards: Valedictorian of the Faculty of Information Technology Vietnam Maritime University,
 University scholarship for excellent achievement in academic semester I and II, Russian Government
 Fully Funded Scholarship for International Students
- Hobbies: Football, Billiards, Learning foreign languages